Jarhead 3: The Siege is a war, action, drama film directed by William Kaufman.
Corporal Evan Albright joined the elite Marine Corps Security Guards to save
the world and see some action-not necessarily in that order.
But his first assignment, protecting a U.
Embassy in a seemingly safe Middle Eastern capitol, relegates his unit to wrangling "gate groupies"
protesting outside the compound and honing their marksmanship by playing video games.
So Albright and his team are caught off guard when well-armed and well-trained militants
launch a surprise attack aimed at killing an informant in the embassy.
Heavily out-gunned, they will have to muster all the courage and fire power they
can as their once routine assignment spirals into all-out war.
Gunny Raines, played by Scott Adkins.
Olivia Winston, played by Sasha Jackson.
Hansen, played by Tom Ainsley.
Major Lincoln, played by Dennis Haysbert.
Evan Albright, played by Charlie Weber.
Blake, played by Dante Basco.
Jarhead is a 2005 biographical war drama film based on the 2003 memoir of the same name by Anthony Swofford,
chronicling his military service in the United States Marine Corps during the Persian Gulf War.
Directed by Sam Mendes, the film stars Jake Gyllenhaal as Swofford with
Jamie Foxx, Peter Sarsgaard, Lucas Black, and Chris Cooper.
Universal Pictures released the film November 4,
2005 to mixed reviews from critics.
It was a box-office disappointment, grossing $97
million against a $72 million budget.
Named for the military slang among U.S.
Marines, the film spawned a direct-to-video series of three
subsequent films, none of which are related to the original.
The tone is emotional.